Roy Mustang observation journal...
What is this?
As it turns out, I've been ordered by
Internal Affairs to inspect my superior officer.
"In order that we may understand how your days are spent,
those who are most suited to the task
are to conduct a top-secret inspection."
So, Lieutenant Havoc,
you're inspecting Colonel Mustang?
Yeah. But I can't investigate him
all on my own.
I want all of you to help me.
"Saturday, 0946 hours:
Colonel Mustang bluntly calls the documents before him that are due at noon to be a pain."
"Similarly, Saturday, 1026 hours:
the Colonel attempted to feed Lieutenant Hawkeye's dog."
"Also, 1103 hours:
the Colonel suddenly began to clean the windows."
"Will he be able to
meet his deadline?"
"1147 hours:
the Colonel begins signing the documents as
he makes a fuss about not having enough time."
"But he did have time."
"In the afternoon, the Colonel conducted an
inspection of the fire-fighting facilities around town."
"At this time, the Colonel received a letter
from the woman working at the flower shop."
"It appears that the letter is an invitation to a date."
"Have witnessed tickets to a play."
"The Colonel readied to leave,
saying he was gathering municipal intelligence, and would go directly home afterward."
"Judging by his face,
he is clearly going on a date."
Just a minute!
The woman at the flower shop! You mean Grace?!
I thought her attitude toward me had cooled off lately. Is that what's going on?!
"What's this, Lieutenant?
You were seeing that girl?"
"You're out of luck
against the Colonel."
"I'm sorry to hear that. Please give up on her."
Stop making light of it!
"How could you guys
know how I feel?!"
"It's your fault you got dumped. No question about it."
"Shut up, you big dope!"
"No, you are!"
"What did you call me?!"
"Attaboy, get him, get him!"
"Don't be so rough on each other.
Let's all get along."
I quit! I quit!
How am I supposed to do this investigation?!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
Here at the Central Command Center,
there are brave soldiers who have no trouble
sacrificing whatever it takes in order to achieve peace.
These are the tales of love and courage of the Flame Alchemist—Colonel Roy Mustang—and his men.
Yo,
Black Hayate.
Sure must be nice for you,
leading a happy-go-lucky life.
What's the matter with
Lieutenant Havoc?
He must've had his heart broken again or something.
That was sharp.
You can't get much time off
when you take on military duties.
It must be hard finding a woman who will go out with you.
He's pathetic.
If he were a man, he'd find a way to handle both his work and women.
It's your fault!
Still, as things are,
it's interfering with his duties.
Hey, someone introduce a woman to Havoc.
Please don't ask the impossible!
I want someone to introduce me!
Colonel, why don't you share one of yours?!
What?
Nothing.
Does anyone know what
kind of woman Havoc likes?
Uh, the other day, when I was out drinking with Havoc,
he complained to me, "Aren't there any
cheerful, well-adjusted beauties out there?"
All right, Warrant Officer Falman,
secure a cheerful,
well-adjusted beauty at once.
Introduce her to Lt. Havoc.
You want me to?!
Remember, you're on a mission.
There's a mission for me?
All the materials on Brig. Gen.
Basque Grand,
Doctor Marcoh, and Shou Tucker.
Also, put together all the records on
the 5th Laboratory and the 2nd Prison.
Right.
Does that include the items
lost in the Central Library fire?
Do not ask me the obvious.
That is why I called on you.
If this can get me into the
Court-Martial Office again,
I might be able to more closely investigate the incident involving Brig. Gen. Hughes.
What is your answer?
Y-Yes! Understood!
A mission, he says.
I haven't had any training in flirting.
What's the world coming to?
I beg your pardon!
Are you all right?!
Scieszka?
Warrant Officer Falman!
Long time no see.
Have you been
getting along okay?
Yes...
more or less.
I know!
Scieszka, I'm looking for a cheerful, well-adjusted beauty right now.
Do you know anyone like that?
Do I know anyone?
So what you're insinuating is that I'm not a cheerful, well-adjusted beauty, huh?
Ah, it's not like that!
Under the Colonel's orders, I have to introduce Lt.
Havoc to a new girlfriend.
Girlfriend?
Do you have anyone in mind?
Oh, in that case,
I have a grand idea!
Major Armstrong's sister?
Yes.
He said that she is of marrying age but is so shy that she cannot find a boyfriend.
Incredible...
I think I'd better go...
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity for you!
If she starts talking about tying the knot, you'll be taking one wealthy wife!
You'll be on easy street!
But I haven't even met her yet.
From what Major Armstrong says,
she has the same dashing looks that he does.
The Major's sister
looks just like him?
That's it, I'm leaving!
Thank you for coming, Lt.
Havoc!
We've been waiting for you!
Well, good luck!
Over the span of 180 years, the Armstrong family has been involved in enterprises
that are deeply tied in with the political and economic affairs of this land.
For generations, it has been a noble family that has served in the military government
and has been a pillar of support
to this nation.
I myself have served in
the military government...
Every time I hear Father tell the story, it is marvelous.
Oh my, Dear,
are you boasting
to the guests again?
Oh, Mother...
Mother?
Thank goodness!
The mother is quite norm—
She's huge!
She's not at all normal!
Hold on a minute now.
The father is wide and fat,
and the mother is long and tall.
Add them together, and their son
would sum up like this.
Which means, when it
comes to their daughter...
Catch me if you can!
No, both parents' features don't always necessarily get passed down.
There's a chance that she leans more toward one side.
Now then, Lieutenant,
allow me to introduce my sister.
Come along, Catherine.
Don't be shy. Come in here.
Which is she?!
Does she take after her father,
or her mother?!
I couldn't stand it either way, but between the two of them,
at least let her
take after her mother!
Um...
Uh...
Nice to meet you.
I'm Catherine Elle Armstrong.
Hooray for mutations!
Well? Isn't she beautiful?
She looks just like me.
Which part?!
Her lower eyelashes, and such.
You don't say.
Come now, Catherine.
Don't be shy.
R-Right.
So, Catherine-san,
what are your hobbies?
Let's see... a little piano...
How cute!
There's no way
this girl is the Major's sister!
I lift a little piano...
What is the matter, Lieutenant?
I take that back.
She absolutely is the Major's sister!
But then again, if you take away her monstrous strength, there's...
her looks...
her figure...
her assets...
and her influence.
Does that make it all okay?
Is this...
the prime of my life?
Catherine-san...
Yes?
If it's all right with you,
would you allow me
the chance to go out with you?
H-Havoc-san...
Yes?
I...
prefer men who are
more like my brother.
Havoc-san, you are not my type,
so let's pretend we never spoke of this.
That is too bad.
Oh? What's the matter, Lieutenant?
10,000 cens says he blows it.
10,000 cens says she turns him down.
Okay, 30,000 cens says
they call the whole thing off.
That doesn't make for
much of a wager, you know.
That's right!
Why did I even come here?
Well, Major Armstrong is exactly the kind of man I figured him for.
Lieutenant Hawkeye,
can you put out a dragnet?
Yes.
I'm starving.
I've had to go without lunch ever since I lost that bet.
I won, so I've been
eating my fill.
Please buy me something!
If I did that, the bet wouldn't mean anything, would it?
Aren't those fixed yet?
I sure do hate this.
The whole area is creepy.
There are even stories of ghosts appearing here.
What's that sound?
It couldn't be...
There it is!
No...
Don't do that...
You're tickling me...
Jeez...
Wait!
Sit!
Shake!
The other one!
Lie down!
All right.
Good morning, Lieutenant.
Morning.
Hey, seriously?
Yes, seriously.
The stories are true!
Give me a break! I won't be able to go out walking at night anymore!
Has something happened?
They say they saw the 13th warehouse.
What nonsense.
It's not nonsense, Colonel!
That's right!
We really are scared here!
The 13th warehouse?
Military warehouses are only supposed to go up to the 12th warehouse.
They say that there's
a 13th one that appears!
In fact, they say that the location where it stands was an execution ground a long time ago!
When night falls,
the 13th warehouse
appears in the place where
there should only be twelve of them!
And the ghosts of those who were executed there long ago
can be heard scra... scraping,
digging up the ground,
looking for their own bodies!
Ha! That's ridiculous.
You look at things in a state of fear,
so you're just imagining the things
that you're afraid of.
You must've just mistook it
for something else.
Colonel, aren't you afraid?
Of course not.
Alchemists are scientists.
It's our job to always look at things
with a logical mind.
But we're not the
only ones who saw it.
There are stories all over the Command Center.
This is pathetic.
You call yourselves soldiers?
I'm going to reveal the reality of the situation
to those who would spread these kinds of stories!
Really?!
Everyone, rejoice!
The Colonel says
he's going to join our operation tonight!
That's our colonel!
He thinks about his men!
Thank goodness! With the Colonel along, there's nothing to be afraid of!
Just a minute!
What are you talking about?
You know, tonight's operation to uncover the truth about the ghostly phenomena.
You're going to show us
the reality of it, right, Colonel?
I did say that, but...
I'm afraid to go home to the dorms at night.
Please help us, Colonel!
For crying out loud, why do I have to
tag along on their little test of courage?!
They all adore you, Colonel.
Why should I be pleased
over being adored by men?
How can men serve as soldiers against flesh-and-blood men,
when something they can't even see makes them jump out of their skin?
I didn't tell you to stop.
You looked like
you wanted to stop.
Oh, Colonel Mustang!
Sorry to drop in on you
so unexpectedly.
I was just in the neighborhood.
My, thank you for taking the trouble to see me.
Go on, Elicia,
can you say hello?
Hey there, Elicia.
How are you?
Well, come on inside.
I'll serve some tea.
No, I still have
some work to attend to,
so I'll be leaving.
Like I said...
It's much more frightening to take on a live person.
Indeed, this is perfect.
There's nothing in here about it.
There aren't any more documents that Hughes left behind, right?
Yes, nothing more.
Fine, then.
Dispose of all of these materials.
Don't even leave ashes.
But these are official
military documents...
I don't care.
The 5th Laboratory
had been shut down.
It's only natural that there wouldn't be any records, wouldn't it?
But there are too few of them.
Even if it was shut down,
it's not natural for there not to be any records of installation maintenance.
Someone was
neglecting their duties.
You mean Brig. Gen. Grand?
What are you trying to say?
That it wasn't a mishap with the records, but that there are no records.
This is evidence that there was
a military directive to cover it up.
Though I couldn't imagine that the Führer was aware of this.
Chimeras that were
formed from humans...
Amplification of alchemic powers
by means of a Philosopher's Stone...
Both would be powerful military assets in battle.
You do know that those techniques are forbidden, right?
Science is the result
of trial and error.
Failing to utilize the mistakes of the past by learning from them,
and abandoning them as being too dangerous would be foolish, would it not?
Right now, I have Zolf Kimbly and Shou Tucker under me.
All I would need is your order.
There's a rebellion
starting up again in Liore.
There is also intelligence that Scar is in hiding.
How would you like to
test your powers there?
Yes, sir.
For Pete's sake... For grown men to all gang up over some ghostly disturbance...
But we really are frightened.
Colonel, having you along will be a great help.
Let's just investigate this quick
and go home!
From here on, the streetlights are out, so there's no light.
What is Maintenance up to?! This is dereliction of duty!
That should do it.
It's just your shadow, you idiot!
Sergeant Fuery, if you do this, you can make shadows fun!
See? It's a cute doggie.
Woof! Woof!
Stop being so scared by everything!
That's easy for you to say.
We really are scared!
I want to go home.
You call yourselves my men?!
Come on! I'll prove to you that there are no ghosts!
Don't leave us behind, Colonel!
Here is Warehouse 12.
Beyond it is just an empty lot.
Look! Where do you
see Warehouse 13?
Maybe it's hiding because
there are a lot of people here.
Enough already!
Could it be that they mean that
when they say 13?
The letter "B" from the alphabet.
It looked like the number 13.
It's true, you could mistake it for that.
So, in the dark and out of fear, what you did was misread it.
Jeez, you're such a scaremonger.
Look! Once you realize what you're dealing with, that's all there is to it!
So, what about the ghosts?
They don't exist!
Thank goodness!
Now I can relax walking past here tomorrow.
Now that you know,
we're done here.
Let's go home!
Now that I can relax,
I'm feeling hungry.
Once we get back,
how about some supper?
You guys are buying tonight.
Huh? I don't have any money!
That's what you get
for scaring us.
Hold it.
What is it?
Look at this.
Looks like something
was dug up here.
It couldn't be...
Falman!
Right.
What's this?
A bone.
Sure enough, it's the ghost of an executed prisoner!
I-It's really here!
Calm down!
Even if this were an execution grounds,
they wouldn't be burying them here too, you know!
This is a case of someone
dumping a body.
A body illegally dumped in a place
said to be a former execution grounds.
There aren't any criminals who would come
all the way onto a military base just to bury this.
Which means, you're saying that
this is an incident internal to the military?
It's highly possible.
It's also possible that this bone belongs to a soldier.
Establishing the identity of
the victim is our top priority!
Do not overlook anything!
They won't necessarily be buried in just one spot.
Dig up anywhere
that looks suspicious.
Roger!
Hey, would you mind if I
told you what I'm thinking?
Who's the one who put us up to this nonsense?!
Has something happened?
Never mind.
Yes?
Colonel, the tiger is on the move.
I'm looking forward to
hearing good things from you.
Excuse me!
What is it?
I request permission to go along with the dispatch eastward.
I have requested Major Armstrong to oversee combat on this trip.
The Major is staying
off the front lines
due to the injuries he sustained in the recent fighting in Ishbal.
I question whether the Major, who has not particularly distinguished himself in battle,
should be given command of the forces on the front line.
I also have a responsibility to this case,
having once been stationed
at the Eastern Command Center.
Please allow me to
go along with them.
I have no objections.
Very well.
Colonel Roy Mustang,
I hereby order you to go along with
the eastern suppression detachment.
I humbly accept your order!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 38: "With the River's Flow"
Whenever I fought...
Whenever I fought with Brother,
I would always hunch down on the bank of the river.